DANIELLE LINDBLOM

FRONTEND ENGINEER

Portfolio: <u>DanielleLindblom.com</u>
GitHub: <u>GitHub.com/Danielle254</u>

LinkedIn: linkedIncom/in/danielle-lindblom/

Missoula, Montana (218) 205 - 4992 <u>Danielle.Lindblom@gmail.com</u>

SUMMARY

Resourceful and considerate engineering professional with 10+ years of experience solving complex problems and improving processes in diverse contexts. Ready to aid your company in producing organized and user-friendly frontend web development solutions. Specialties include: React, JavaScript, Accessibility, Continuous Process Improvement, and Technical Training and Documentation.

SKILLS

Software Engineering:

React, JavaScript, HTML & CSS, Git & GitHub, Sass, Object-Oriented Programming, Accessibility, Unit Testing

Professional:

Continuous Improvement, Technical Training & Documentation, Team Leadership, Project Management, Mentoring, Proactive Communication, Working Collaboratively

PROJECTS

Chingu | September 2024 - Present

Worked collaboratively with a crossfunctional team of developers, designer, and product owner using Agile Methodology and React to create and deliver a real-world project in 6 weeks while maintaining a focus on accessibility and usability.

Codedex Hackathon | July 2024

Led my team to create a working, animated single page website in 24 hours utilizing React, CSS, GitHub, and effective time management.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota -Minneapolis

Bachelor of Science - Mechanical Engineering

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Implementation Specialist

Submittable | Feb 2022 - June 2024

- Designed a multi-stage custom automation workflow for customer IFF that utilized the Submittable API to reduce manual staff hours by 50% resulting in improved grant management
- Built and deployed the multi-lingual intake form for the State of Minnesota's Tax Rebate Program in under 1 week while emphasizing accessibility, resulting in smooth data collection, no interference with custom automations, and the distribution of \$1B to Minnesota citizens
- Identified, tested, and reported bugs in live production leading to more accurate reporting of issues, reduced customer frustration, and increased customer retention

Continuous Improvement Specialist

Blue Cross Blue Shield of Minnesota | Aug 2019 - Feb 2020 Pentair | April 2015 - March 2017 Collins Aerospace | July 2013 - July 2015

- Planned, coordinated, and executed a 12-month Lean
 Transformation project at Pentair for the 2-shift, 100 employee
 Cooling Assembly Area by leading cross-functional teams
 through several week-long kaizen process improvement events
 resulting in \$650k annual cost savings, 25% faster time to
 manufacture, and greatly improved employee morale
- Achieved Lean Practitioner Certification 2014

Small Business Owner

Danielle Lindblom Coaching | Oct 2018 - Feb 2022 High Spirits Dog Training | July 2014 - Aug 2019

- Built and updated websites for both businesses using Wix.com
- Managed all Business to Customer sales
- Specialized in Behavior Science and Change Management